skift.com 2018-12-22

# Privacy Policy – Skift

**UPDATED AND REVISED AS OF SEPTEMBER 26, 2018**

This User Agreement and Privacy Policy governs each website, mobile site, application, and/or other service, regardless of how distributed, transmitted, published, or broadcast (each, a “Service”) provided by Skift, Inc and its subsidiaries and/or affiliates (“we,” “us,” or “our”) that links to this User Agreement and Privacy Policy, which is binding on all those who access, visit and/or use the service, whether acting as an individual or on behalf of an entity, including you and all persons, entities, or digital engines of any kind that harvest, crawl, index, scrape, spider, or mine digital content by an automated or manual process or otherwise (collectively, “you” or “your”).

At Skift, we very much appreciate your readership and understand the importance of your personal privacy. This policy is available to help you understand the handling of information while you’re on the site. On this page, we’ll explain our approach to achieving GDPR-compliance, both for ourselves and for you.

### HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION

Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, that is not otherwise publicly available. Skift collects personal information in a variety of ways, including when you subscribe to or use Skift products or services; when you subscribe to Skift newsletters, daily, weekly, speciality, and similar email notices; when you register for or participate in Skift Forum and other events such as, virtual educational programs such as seminars, webinars, etc., that Skift conducts from time to time; when you visit Skift website or the websites of certain Skift Partners; and when you enter Internet-based contests, promotions or sweepstakes sponsored or administered by Skift; when you download reports or editorial pieces such as Oral History Projects, digital magazines, etc; and when you purchase Skift Products such as Research Subscription.

When you register on our website or for our products and services, we ask for and collect information such as, but not limited to; your name, email address, company, job title, country, zip code, and industry. For some products and services we may also ask for your address and information about you or your business’s assets or income. Once you register with Skift and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us.

If you are purchasing something from a Skift website, we need to know personal information such as your name, email address, mailing address, credit card number, and expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. This information may also be used by Skift to notify you of related products and services. Credit card information will not be shared or sold to unaffiliated third parties for any purpose without your express permission, except as necessary to process the transaction.

### TRANSPARENCY AND CHOICE

People have different privacy concerns. Our goal is to be clear about what information we collect, so that you can make meaningful choices about how it is used. For example:

  * Wherever it is optional to collect additional information about you, we transparently inform you about what information we need, why we ask for it and we require your consent to process such information. When you change your mind, there is always a convenient way how to let us know.
  * You can always set your own Cookie preferences and therefore decide whether you agree to be on our radar when it comes to ads or behavior analytics or not.

### COOKIES AND RELATED TECHNOLOGIES

We collect information through technology, such as cookies, pixels, and Web beacons, including when you visit our websites. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Skift or its advertisers may send a cookie to your computer through your browser. Skift uses cookies to track page requests and the duration of each user’s visit, and the use of cookies allows us to provide a user’s browser with information tailored to the visitor’s preferences and needs and to also streamline the user’s visits to our website. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of your browser. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or allow your browser to show you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept cookies, your experience at our website and other websites may be diminished and some features may not work as intended. Pixel tags are tiny graphic images that tell us what parts of the website have been visited or measure the effectiveness of searches users perform on the website. We may also use pixel tags in email messages to tell us whether emails have been opened to assure that we are only sending messages that are of interest to our users.

In addition, Skift automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, Skift cookie information, and the website page you request. Skift uses this information to help diagnose problems with our servers, for system administration, and to examine our website traffic in aggregate. The information may be collected and used to improve the content of our Web pages and to customize content and/or layout for each user.

Please note that Skift may allow third party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Among other things, these third parties may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to enable such third parties to record which ads your browser has loaded and which pages you may have been viewing when the ads were delivered or accessed. Advertisers’ use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the Skift Privacy Policy.

### USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Registration is not required in order to use this site. However, Skift may provide comments, polls, submission forms, etc. to its users. You may be required to register for these features. If you do register, and in the process provide us with personally identifiable information, no information will be shared with any third-party organization except with your express consent. If you post comments or articles on the site, any personally identifiable information you provide in those comments or articles will be public. As such, we are not responsible for personally identifiable information that you may choose to share through these channels.

We also provide visitors the opportunity to sign up to receive communications from us. In this case, we ask the visitor for personally identifiable information. Depending on what the visitor opts-in for, these communications will include some or all of the following: daily or weekly newsletters, company updates, and/or other relevant promotions. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in any email we send, or by replying to any email stating you’d like to removed from our list.

We may use personal information collected through its website to send out targeted email promotions on behalf of its advertisers and industry partners.

If you participate in a Skift virtual programs such as Skift Talks, webinars, or other time-sensitive programs, we use personal information to contact you to remind you of upcoming deadlines or additional information concerning these programs.

Skift occasionally conducts subscriber and/or user surveys to better target our content to our audiences. The aggregated information collected is sometimes shared with our advertisers, however, we do not share specific individual information with third parties.

Skift operates several websites featuring its travel-related content and services. Skift may share personal information collected from users of its websites internally across these websites to better serve its users.

Skift has numerous products and services and therefore numerous email and promotion lists. In an effort to allow users to tailor their participation in Skift services and promotions, Skift provides users the ability to choose specific lists or products of interest and opt-out options are product and use/list specific. All email promotions sent from Skift provide an opt-out link at the bottom of the email pursuant to which users can opt-out of specific products and promotions. If you receive one of these emails and wish to unsubscribe please follow the instructions given in each email or contact [infosecurity@skift.com](mailto:infosecurity@skift.com).

If you provide financial information, we use that information primarily to verify your credit and collect payments for your purchases, orders, subscriptions, etc.

If you provide us with personally identifiable information for the purposes of receiving these communications, this information will not be shared with any third-party organization except with your express consent. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer wish us to possess your information, you can request correction, updating, or deletion of your information by emailing us at [infosecurity@skift.com](mailto:infosecurity@skift.com).

### SHARING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

Skift does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

We may provide personal information about our users to trusted partners and vendors who work on behalf of or with Skift under confidentiality and similar agreements prohibiting such parties’ further use of the information. These companies may use your personal information to help Skift communicate with you about offers from Skift and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to use or share this information.

When you register for a contest, event, virtual trade-show, or other promotion that is sponsored by a third party, the third party will be provided personal information unless otherwise posted in connection with the promotion. This is noted on all forms upon submission.

### DISPLAY OF ADVERTISING

Skift or one of our web-advertising partners may deliver ads appearing on the website to users of our website. Our web-advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers only the use of cookies by Skift and does not cover the use of cookies by any third party advertisers.

### CRITEO ADVERTISING

As you browse the Skift websites, advertising cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partner, Criteo, then enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with Skift. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address or telephone number. You can visit [this page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) to opt out of Criteo and their partners’ targeted advertising.

### OUTSIDE LINKS

This website may contain links to other websites that are not controlled by us. We are not responsible for the privacy practices and policies of any website other than our own.

### SECURITY

We follow accepted industry standards to protect personal information you have provided.

We work hard to protect Skift and our users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information we hold. In particular:

  * We encrypt our services using SSL, in transit and at rest as well.
  * We review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems.
  * We restrict access to personal information to those of Skift staff, and third parties who need to know that information in order to process it for us, and who are subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

However, no method of electronic storage can ever be 100% secure. Therefore we are not in a position to guarantee the absolute security of your information.

### LEGAL DISCLAIMER

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on our website.

### UPDATE/CHANGE YOUR USER PROFILE OR PREFERENCES

To update your email address or change your email preferences please contact [infosecurity@skift.com](mailto:infosecurity@skift.com).

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Skift reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the website. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the website. Users will be informed of changes to this Privacy Policy via the “updated as of” notice on this Policy.

We’re committed to our users enjoying Skift to help them understand and prepare for the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). The GDPR is the most comprehensive EU data privacy law in decades, and will come into effect on May 25, 2018.

As well as strengthening and unifying user data privacy across the EU, it also puts new or additional obligations upon anyone that handles EU citizens’ personal data, regardless of where they are located.

Below, we’ll explain our approach to achieving GDPR-compliance, both for ourselves and for our Customers.

### SKIFT WAY AND ADOPTION

The GDPR’s updated requirements are significant and our team is working hard to bring Skift’s service offerings and contractual commitments in line so Customers can prepare themselves before May 25, 2018. Measures taken to achieve this include:

  *  **Changes in our newsletter sign ups.** We updated all opt-in checkboxes to require an action taken. All language with exactly what you are signing up for is on forms/landing pages across products.
  *  **Investments under the hood.** We are working on improvements to our infrastructure, to fulfill all the requirements and obligations connected to continuous security monitoring, data breaches and security incident management.
  *  **Legal matters.** Any Customer willing to enter into a Data Processing Addendum (“DPA”) with Skift is welcome to use our template. Please reach out to us at infosecurity@skift.com to learn more about next steps.
  *  **Policies.** We have already updated our Privacy Policy. This is not the end of the story, we are working on our internal policies and practices to ensure that we are aligned with the GDPR requirements.

We’ll also continue to monitor the guidance around GDPR compliance from privacy-related regulatory bodies, and will adjust our plans accordingly if it changes.

### STAY UPDATED

Fulfilling our privacy and data security commitments is important to us. So we’re happy to help you prepare for all the changes the GDPR brings. This page will be revised to reflect GDPR-related information as it becomes available. If you have any questions about how Skift can help you with compliance, we hope you’ll reach out to us at [infosecurity@skift.com](mailto:infosecurity@skift.com).

This privacy policy applies to all Skift websites including <http://skift.com/>; <https://research.skift.com/>; <https://forum.skift.com/>, [https://airlineweekly.skift.com](https://airlineweekly.skift.com/), [https://wellness.skift.com](https://wellness.skift.com/) and all sites with this domain including, but not limited to <https://forum.skift.com/europe/>, <https://forum.skift.com/tech/>, <https://forum.skift.com/newyork/>, <https://edu.skift.com/>, <https://skiftx.com/>, <https://table.skift.com/>, <http://gadling.com/>.

### CONTACT DETAILS

If you have any questions regarding this policy, please email [infosecurity@skift.com](mailto:infosecurity@skift.com).
